I've had this image in my head ever since I was a child.
子供のごろから
私の頭の中にイメージがあった
An image of a generic landscape you could find anywhere.
それはどこにでもありそうな風景
A scene from a dream that I have all the time.
幾度となく見続けてる夢の景色
I've never been there, though.
けれど私はその場所に行ったことがない
I've been told it's because I've undergone In-Grove's Anti-Feminus,
イングローブのアンチフェミナスを受けたせいだと言われたけど
but it didn't really matter why.
ホントは理由なんてどうでも良かった
ただ私は何かを探したかったのだ
I just wanted an excuse to find something.
That's why I went on this trip.
だから私は旅に出た
エマージェンシー
An emergency?!
デブリ帯にバンプって
I'm hitting debris? Why?
なんで
There aren't any cleaners this far out!
辺境だからクリーナーなんて
お願いりのん
Come on...
Rinon, take control of the ship!
船体制御
船体安定次第ショットジャンプ
Make a short jump as soon as the ship is stable!
なあ
Please!
お願い私をあの場所まで連れて行って
Take me to that planet!
Don't die on me...
あと少し
落下予定位置に生体反応
There's a life sign in the crash zone?!
私はきっとその場所を求めている
I think...
this is what I was looking for.
七海さん七海さん
Nanami!
柑菜ちゃん
Kanna?
Oh man, I had the weirdest dream.
やだお姉ちゃん変な夢見ちゃった
A naked girl was holding Kai surrounded by a ball of light.
何かね光の中で海君が裸の女の人に抱きかかえられててね
She was really cute...
そうとても可愛いらしい
ううんとっても美しい女の子だったわ
More than that, beautiful.
She looked just like...
そうそうちょうどそこにいる女の子みたい
her.
七海さん
Nanami!
どういうことか説明してもらえるかしら
Care to explain this?
Let me say this first.
最初に言っとくけど誤解しないでほしいんだ
Don't get me wrong here.
What's there to get wrong?
どういう誤解
All the things you're getting wrong right now without saying it.
君が心の中で思っているようなこと
Anyway, she's...
とにかく彼女は
Takatsuki Ichika.
貴月イチカ先輩
She transferred to a third-year class in our school today.
今日うちの学校の三年に転入してきた人
Yeah...
正解
Takatsuki Ichika?
貴月イチカさんね
はじめまして海君のお姉ちゃんの七海です
Nice to meet you.
I'm Kai's sister, Nanami.
Sorry for the trouble.
お邪魔しております
Glad to hear.
されてます
You only met her this morning, so why is she here?
で今日出合ったばかりの先輩がどうして海君のうちにいるわけ
W-Well...
そそれは
じ実はクワンリンケージに不具合が出て
Actually...
there was a sudden failure in the quantum link,
and then my ultorate was badly damaged,
オルタレイトに深刻な被害が出たため行く宛てが無くそのうえ
and the inclove suffered serious damage as well, so...
インクローブにもそれはもう甚大な被害が
All that's just going over my head.
難しくてお姉ちゃんよく分かんない
Basically, she has no place to stay anymore because of various reasons,
要するにトラブルで住むところがなくなって
and she has no money either, I think.
しかもお金も持っていないらしいんだ
I ran into her on my way home,
学校の帰りに偶然先輩と会って
and when she told me about the mess she's in, I offered to let her crash here tonight.
その話聞いて
じゃあ一晩だけでも泊めてあげようかなって
だって放っておけないでしょう
I couldn't just leave her.
She would've had to camp on the riverbank all alone.
女の人一人で野宿させるわけにはいかないし
I see, I see...
そういうことだったの
Question!
質問どうして玄関先で抱き合ってたんですか
Why were you holding him by the front door?
そんなことしてないって
I told you, she didn't do that.
Well...
あれは
えっしたんですか
What, you did?
Kaito's ultorate was...
海人君のオルタレイトに
I mean, he wasn't feeling well, so I was just taking care of him!
いえ具合が悪いようだったので
介抱してたんです
ああそうだった
Now that you mention it, I felt sick and passed out...
なんか俺気分が悪くなって意識がなくなって
Are you sick, Kai?
海君病気なの
分かんないけど今は大丈夫
I don't know... I'm fine now.
介抱介抱ですか
You took care of him, huh?
Holding him close to you so he'd get better...
そばに付き添って抱きしめる
文字通り介抱というわけですね
That's "taking care of him," all right.
抱きしめたら病気が治っちゃうとでも
Did you think he'd get better if you held him?
私の星ではああするんです
That's how we do it on my planet.
On your planet?
わ私の故郷です
I mean, in my homeland.
Where are you from?
貴月さんはどちらのご出身
From Pleia— I mean, from the North.
プレア……いいえあの北のほうです
From Hokkaido?
北海道とかですか
No, farther.
いいえもっと遠くから
From overseas?
留学ですか
Yeah, sort of.
ううんそんな感じです
へえそんな遠いところから一人で留学しに来たんだ
You came here all alone from so far away to study!
That's wonderful! And your Japanese is great too!
貴月さん偉い日本語もとっても上手だし
どどうもなるほどなんとなくですけど
Th-Thank you...
Okay, I guess things are starting to make sense now.
事情は飲み込めました
それはよかった
And boy, am I glad.
Why didn't you call your parents after you ran into trouble, though?
でもトラブルがあったのなら
実家のご両親に連絡とかすればよかったんじゃないんですか
Well... I...
それはその
What is it?
Did something happen to your...
あの何か事情でも
I get it all now!
お姉ちゃんなんとなく分かる
Get what?!
エスパー
Takatsuki... No, Ichika.
貴月さんあっううんイチカちゃん
I'm so sorry I reminded you of your loss.
ごめんなさいね悲しいことを思い出させてしまって
Kaito and I lost our parents too, so I can feel for...
私と海君も両親失ってるから
イチカちゃんの気持ちが
I can really feel for you!
イチカちゃんの気持ちが痛いほど分かるわ
Nanami?
ちょっ七海さん
Anyway, there's your explanation.
まあさとにかくそういうわけだからさ
姉さん一晩だけでも先輩を家に泊めてあげてもいいだろう
Can't we let her stay here tonight?
Tonight? Don't be stingy!
一晩なんて言わないでここに住めばいいんじゃないかしら
She should move in!
Nanami?!
七海さん
I mean, I'll be leaving for a pretty long business trip tomorrow.
ほら私明日から長期出張するし
誰かに海君の面倒を見てもらわなきゃって思っていたの
Someone'll need to take care of Kai anyway.
I think I can trust one of his upperclassmen.
同じ学校の先輩さんなら安心だし
女の子だからお料理やお洗濯もできるだろうし
And since she's a girl, she could cook and do the laundry as well.
I'll do my best!
が頑張ります
頼もしいわ
That's a load off my mind!
Are you off your rocker, Nanami?
七海さん安易です
You can't just let a teenage boy and girl live under the same roof!
年頃の男女が同じ屋根の下で暮らすだなんて
困ったときはお互い様
People have to help each other when they're on hard times.
Besides, Kai's a nice guy, so just because he's living with a really cute girl,
それに海君はやさしい子だから
いくらきれいな先輩さんと一緒に暮らすからといって
doesn't mean he'd try anything funny.
変なことや変なことや変なことはしないでしょう
Am I right?
しないでしょう
ももちろんです
Naturally.
あ今間がありました
I could feel the hesitation! You had to think about it!
ちょっと考えてましたよ
I didn't hesitate!
考えてねえよその目はウソの目だ
I can see it in your eyes!
See what?
どんな目だよ
You know what!
どんなのってそうなの
All right, meeting adjourned.
じゃあこれで決まり
不束者ですがよろしくお願いしますお姉さん
I doubt I can be of any use, but I will try, Sister.
Just call me Sis.
お姉ちゃんよ
Okay, Sistersis.
はいおねえちゃんさん
なんか嫁入り前みたい
This is like a wedding arrangement.
I'll walk Tanigawa home.
じゃあ谷川んちまで送ってくる
なんか怒ってる
Are you... angry?
No.
そんなことない
Listen, Tanigawa.
あのさ谷川先輩のことは
About her...
人助けだよね
You're just helping her out, right?
困ってる先輩を助けてあげただけだよね
You're just helping her 'cause she's in trouble, right?
Yeah, that's it.
ああそうだよそれだけだよ
じゃあ信じる
Okay, I believe you.
ここでいいからじゃあまたあした
I'll be fine from here.
See you tomorrow!
またあしたか
See you... tomorrow...
ええあの美人の先輩さんが霧島君の家に下宿
The pretty new girl moved in with him?
どういうことなの柑菜
What's going on, Kanna?
I don't know.
分かんないけどなし崩し的にそういうことになっちゃったの
It just kind of built up to that.
He has his family around, you know.
でも霧島君の家にはご家族もいるんだし
Just his sister, and she's leaving for a business trip tomorrow.
お姉さん明日から長期出張なの
おいおいマジかよ
What, are you kidding me?
That changes everything.
急展開じゃないの
どうしようか哲郎君
What should we do, Tetsuro?
これで決まりだな
Why, isn't it obvious?
決まりって何が
What is?
We'll meet at his place tomorrow.
あしたやるミーティングの待ち合わせ場所
I'm home!
ただいま
お帰りなさい
Welcome back.
Dinner is ready.
ご飯できてますよ
What's wrong?
どうかした
Oh, it's nothing.
いやなんでもないです
So... where's my sister?
えっと姉さんは
荷造りが残っているからって
She still has to pack up, so she ate earlier. She's upstairs.
先に食事をして部屋にいるわ
ああそうですか
I see.
Pasta with miso soup?
パスタと味噌汁
Standard course, right?
定番でしょう
Not together.
組み合わせ以外は
何か間違ってた
Did I do something wrong?
いいやいいんです
Nothing, don't sweat it.
Thanks for the food.
いただきます
How is it?
どう
Are you all right?
大丈夫
Is it bad?
おいしくなかった
No, it's not that...
いやおいしくないって言うか
But it's a bit sour and...
この味酸味があって
Did you cool this?
これ冷やし中華
Yeah, I thought something cold would be better after such a hot day.
うん今日暑かったから冷たいものがいいと思って
I'm just a bit surprised by the taste...
いや予想外の味だったんでびっくりしただけで
Your cold pasta is great!
うんイケますよこの冷やしバスタ
Can I ask you something?
質問してもいいですか
Sure.
何
Why did you come here to study?
先輩は何でここに留学しに来たんですか
I was looking for a certain place.
行きたい場所があったから
What place?
どこですこの辺なんですか
Somewhere around here?
I could help you find it...
よかったら案内しますよ
I don't know.
それがね分からないの
分からないって
How can you not know?
There were trees, a lake...
木があって池があって
There's nothing special about it.
何の特徴もない場所なんだけど
That kinda makes it hard to find.
それじゃ探しようが
そうだよね
Yeah.
But I want to find it anyway.
でも行きたいの
What a hell of a day.
怒涛の一日だった
Tomorrow I have to face the others.
でもって明日は打ち合わせで皆と会うんだよな
How will I explain all this?
どうやって説明するか
On the matter of unexplained, what's this?
そういえばこれ何なんだ
増えてる
Are they spreading?
That reminds me...
そういやさっきも
抱きしめたら病気が治っちゃうとでも
But can you even cure him that way?
抱きしめる
She held me...
Oh my, Kai. I need to treat this at once.
あらあら大変すぐに治療しなくちゃ
痛いの痛いの飛んで行け
This will make it better.
Quit dreaming, man.
なんってねあるわけねえし
That sucks.
ダメだわ修復は無理そう
This looks impossible to fix.
りのんクワンリンケージの方は
How is the quantum link, Rinon?
Great. Glitches.
見事にバグってる
後悔なんてしない
There's nothing to regret.
I managed to reach this planet after all.
この星に来れたんだから
I must've been really tired
疲れがたまっていたのか
僕は布団に潜り込むなりすぐに眠ってしまった
because I fell asleep as soon as I hit the bed.
夢も見なかった
I didn't dream, either.
Episode Two
With you...
海人君海人君
Kaito! Kaito! Wake up, Kaito!
起きて海人君
Sistersis says she's on her way out.
お姉ちゃんさんがもうすぐ出かけるって
Is it already that la—
もうそんな時間
What is it?
な何
その服
That gown...
ああお姉ちゃんさんから借りたの
I borrowed it from Sistersis.
でもこの土地の寝間着ってちょっと恥ずかしいよね
But it's a bit revealing, isn't it?
You can say that again!
そそそそそうですね
Kai! I need to catch my flight!
海君お姉ちゃん出かけるわよ
I'll cry if you don't see me off!
お見送りしてくれないと泣いちゃうんだから
Hang on!
今行くから
Pond of the Full Moon
海人君病気には気をつけて
Kaito, don't get sick, okay?
Don't throw money out the window.
生活費を使え過ぎないように
Take school seriously, be nice to your friends, and don't stay up too late.
勉強もしっかりお友達と仲良く夜深しないで
Take care and be a good boy!
寂しいから元気でね
Ichika, please look after him.
イチカちゃん海君のことよろしく
Come on. The train is leaving.
ほらもう時間だよ
ああやっと行ったよ
What a relief.
Kaito.
海人君
さみしい
Lonely?
A little, I guess.
まあ少しは
Oh, that's right.
ああそうだ先輩
There's something we have to do before we go home.
帰る前にちょっとよりたいところがあるんです
What is it?
よりたいところ
Something my sister asked me to do.
姉さんに頼まれて
Your sister did?
お姉ちゃんさんに
Yeah. She told me to get you some clothes.
えさすがに私服がないのはまずいでしょう
She's a bit of an odd one,
なんかちょっと変わったところもあるけど
でも
but she's really cute.
可愛い人だな
This should do for the time being.
これだけあれば大丈夫ですよね
ありがとうすっごく楽しかった
Thanks! This was so much fun!
I guess all girls love shopping.
やっぱり買い物は女の子の醍醐味よね
お姉ちゃんさんにもお礼を言わなくちゃ
I'll have to say thanks to Sistersis as well.
こうから連絡が来たときでいいですよ
Just do that when she calls.
I will.
うんそうする
あれ開いてる
What? It's open.
なんでは
Why...
You're late.
あら遅かったわね
待ちくたびれたわ
I got sick of waiting.
よお帰りなさい
Hey!
Welcome home!
What is this?
ななんで
We were going to meet up today to talk about the movie, right?
昨日映画制作の決起集会するって言ったろう
Sorry about this, but we all decided to meet here.
悪いが集合場所は勝手に海んちに決めさせてもらった
That's not how it works!
そうじゃなくて
Looks like you had a lot of fun shopping...
早速仲良くお買い物ですか
That's not the issue here!
そそうでもなくて
How did you all get in here anyway?
だいたいどうやって家に入ったんだよ
もう少し丈夫な鍵を使ったほうがいいわよ
You might want to install a better lock.
Don't just unlock it without asking.
勝手に開けないでください
I could call the cops, you know!
思い切り犯罪ですって
あらだってちゃんと調べておかないとね
Sorry, I had to check out
where my best friend moved in.
親友の下宿先を
How do you know that?!
どどうしてそれを
あっ谷川
Tanigawa!
Now that everyone's turned up,
それでは全員集まったところで
let us commence the first discussions about the content of the movie directed by Kirishima Kaito.
私達有志による第一回
霧島海人監督作品の内容について
話し合いを始めます
Let us begin, then.
始めますったら始めます
'Sup, Director!
よ監督
Do you have to call me that?
なんだよそりゃったく
Why is she in charge again?
つうかなんであの人が仕切ってんだ
Being two grades higher has to have its benefits.
いいじゃんか上級生だし
So what's our movie going to be about?
それでどんな映画にするんですか
Mobile
We're going to adapt this script.
私が書いたこの脚本を映像化します
Mobile
It's been in my head for twenty years and more or less on paper for five.
ちなみに構想２０年執筆期間は５年
What?!
おい
What's the plot?
でどんなストーリーなの
Set in the 23rd century when mecha are commonly used,
２３世紀に機動兵器が世界を股にかけて活躍する
this movie is world-class entertainment that would put even Hollywood to shame.
ハリウッドもハダカで逃げ出す一大エンターテイメント作品よ
Forget it.
無理です
It's all CG. We can do it.
すべてＣＧでやるから大丈夫
But then what's Kai's camera for?
カメラが必要ないかも
Shouldn't we go with something simpler?
無難な内容にしたほうがいいんじゃない
So what about slice-of-life?
なら学園モノとかじゃねえ
撮影許可ぐらい学校も出してくれると思うし
I bet the school would let us set it there.
I guess it's the easy way out.
まあ確かに無難だな
ストーリーは
So what about the plot?
Okay, get this.
こういうのはどうかしら
Zombies invade the school, and the few people left alive—
学園に突如ゾンビが発生
生き残った主人公たちが
Forget it.
無理です
Do you have any ideas, Ichika?
イチカ先輩リクエストあります
You've got balls, I'll give you that.
霧島君あなたなかなかいい度胸ね
Me?
私
You're part of the main cast, so feel free to suggest anything!
主演なんだから希望言ってください
Hey, stop!
そそんな
I have no suggestions for the plot,
ストーリーじゃないんだけど綺麗な風景が見たいかな
but I'd love some nice landscape shots.
I'm new here, so I'd like to go around and get to know the area.
私ここに来たばっかりだし
いろんな場所に行って
いろいろなものを見てみたいな
I was looking for a certain place.
いきたい場所があったから
あっごめんなさい抽象的で
Sorry, maybe that's too vague.
いいんじゃないですかいろいろと行きましょう
I'm fine with that.
Let's go to all sorts of places.
Summer break is just around the corner.
もうすぐ夏休みなんだし
I like it!
いいね遊びと映画の撮影一粒で二度おいしい
We could have fun and shoot the movie at the same time.
Two birds with one stone!
I think we'd just mess around.
きっと遊んでばっかりになると思うけど
No harm in that!
それはそれでいいじゃんか
It's not like our life depends on making this movie.
絶対に映画作んなきゃいけないわけでもないんだし
いろんな場所に行って見ましょうよ
Let's go around and see places.
Maybe you'll find what you're looking for.
いきたい場所を見つかるかもしれないし
Thank you, Kaito!
ありがとう海人君
Let's talk about the contents later.
映画の内容はこれから考えるとして
For now, let's raise a toast and pray for the movie's success.
まずは映画の完成を願って
皆で乾杯しましょう
Well then... Cheers!
では乾杯
Cheers!
乾杯
What is this?
なんですこの飲み物
変わった味だね
It tastes weird.
でもほんのり甘くて美味しいかも
I like how sweet it is.
Can I have more?
おかわりあります
ええたくさん持ってきたから
Sure.
I brought a lot. Drink as much as you want.
心ゆくまで飲んで頂戴
革命そして上がり
Reverse! And I'm out!
Excellent.
ニヤリ
ねえ檸檬先輩
Hey, Lemon.
この飲み物を何っていうんですか
Whatcha call this stuff?
ダイナマイトドリンク
Dynamite Drink.
なるほどそれは引きますね
All righty! Awesome name!
ダイナマイトか
Dynamite, huh?
先輩大丈夫ですか
Hey, you all right?
I spazed out for a moment.
なんだかぼうっとしちゃって
"Spazed out"?
ぼうっと
うんちょっと体が熱くて
Dunno, I just feel so hot...
体が
You're hot...
そそうですか
I see!
That's not good, is it?
それは大変ですね
What's that? No private chats!
こら二人っきり何してる
Bring it inside!
こっち来い
What's gotten into you, Tanigawa?
な何だよ谷川
Oh, were you in the middle of something?
今私のことお邪魔だと思ったでしょう
What a shame!
思ったでしょう
Nope, all good.
そんなことないです
先輩はどうなんです
What about you?
I'm good.
思ってないわよ
ここに下宿するんですよね
You live here, right?
You two are living together.
二人っきりで暮らすんだ
ああそうなのな
Yeah, I guess.
Summer break is about to start.
もうすぐ夏休み一日中二人っきり
It'll be just you two all day.
二人っきり
Just you two all day!
Well, yeah...
いやまあ
Ichika!
イチカ先輩
Yes!
はっあはい
Lemme be frank, aw'right?
単刀直入に聞きますけど
What do you think of Kaito?
先輩は海人君のことをどう思ってるんですか
Well, uh...
そそれは海人君は困った時に助けてくれた人で
Kaito helped me out when I was in trouble...
Don't play dumb!
そうじゃなくて
I asked if you have a crush on him!
どう思ってるかお聞いてるんです
Well...
それは
Why?
ななんで
なんだよこれ
This is hilarious!
I-It's a biological... I mean, my pet.
生体じゃなくて
私のぺペットなの
It's called Rinon.
名前はりのん
Are there animals like this?
こんな動物いるか
What a weird little thing!
So cute!
And it's dancing!
Now, as the high point of the day,
さあ興が乗ってきたところで
私の特製王様ゲームを始めましょう
let's play my own version of Simon Says.
Simon Says?
王様ゲームって
いいですね
面白そう
やれば分かるわ
You'll get it as we go.
Who's Simon?
王様誰だ
私だ
I am.
Let's get this going.
では軽めに
Number three: Flick number one's forehead, as hard as you can.
三番一番にデコピン
全力で
Ouch!
いてえ
四番一番を叩く
Number four: Slap number one.
海人のバカ
You idiot!
なんで俺ばっかり
Why always me?
Number five: Kiss number four.
五番四番にキス
Number three: Take off your pants.
三番ズボンを脱ぐ
Sure thing!
はい
Hey, don't start stripping in front of girls!
おい何パンツに手かけてんだよ
Freak!
変態
Number four: Show us the seductress.
四番女豹のポーズ
そして二番
Number two...
わ私
Me?
With number one...
一番と
have sex.
エッチ
Game's off!
できるか
素敵よ皆
Great work, everyone.
とてもいい映画になりそうだわ
This'll be a great movie.
海人君
Kaito,
大丈夫？
are you all right?
Yeah, more or less.
ああまあなんとか
What about you?
先輩こそ
私はもう大丈夫
I'm all right now.
That's good.
そうですか
I wonder what that dri—
けど何だだんですかね
あの飲み物
My head... suddenly...
あれ急に頭が
Kaito?!
海人君
Sorry.
すみません先輩
Close your eyes for a minute.
少し目を閉じて
Activate.
りのん
I looked for the reason why I fell in love
どう
How do you feel?
あれ痛みが
It doesn't hurt anymore.
and tried solemn words
Glad to hear it.
良かった
Idiot...
バカ
Once I realized my feelings,
海君のバカ
Kai, you idiot...
I'm the idiot.
バカは俺だな
the threads had gotten hopelessly tangled up
Hey...
先輩
先輩俺
I...
If I'd been able to say it without hesitation
俺は
Don't.
ダメ
Don't say it.
言っちゃダメ
you wouldn't have to cry now
Please
お願い
言わないで
don't say it.
You Will Say It...
Episode Three
Kanna, I heard Kirishima's taking the day off!
We've got to drop in! Top priority!
You can't be serious.
柑菜霧島君とお休みだって
大変お見舞いに行かなきゃ
最優先実行で
ああ言ってはいけないセリフは